The Hidden Plot Set Into Motion
(我愛羅)視神経がつながった。
My optic nerve is connected.
(ケゴン)フウ！
(ヨウロウ)待て！ どこへ行く気だ！
Foo!
Wait!
Where do you think you're going?!
(ケゴン)巻物は揃ってる。
まっすぐ中央塔へ向かうんだ！
We have both scrolls!
So let's head straight
for the central tower!
I don't want to!
(フウ)や～だ！ だってまだ
友達一人も出来てないもん。
I still haven't made any friends!
(フウ)それに もう少し遊んでから
行くっす！
I just want to have
a little more fun first!
(ヨウロウ)おい！ 忘れたか！
Have you already forgotten?!
We're taking the Chunin Exams to make
a name for the Hidden Waterfall!
中忍試験は
滝隠れの名をあげるため！
We may not beat
the 97-minute record
(ケゴン)下忍時代の風影の97分という
記録には及ばなくても➡
set by the Kazekage
when he was a genin,
せめて せめて一番槍のほまれを！
but we can still shoot
for first place!
(フウ)ひゃっほ～い！
(ヨウロウ/ケゴン)うっ！ 聞いてない！
Yahoo!
– She's not listening!
うぅ…。
落ち着け。
ああ。
Calm down.
Yeah…
(ヨウロウ)フウ！ そんなことでは
里長がお嘆きになられますぞ！
Foo, the village chief would
be disappointed if he saw you now!
シブキが？
Shibuki...?!
(ケゴン)ああ そうだ。
滝隠れの名をあげるのは➡
Yes, bringing glory
to the Hidden Waterfall
何より シブキ様の願い。
is Lord Shibuki's greatest wish!
《フウ : シブキ…》
Shibuki…
シブキ様が 何と思われるか。
Think of how he would feel!
わかった わかったっす！
しかたないっすね。
Okay, okay!
I guess I have no choice.
《ケゴン : フウには 里長の名を出すのが
いちばんだな》
The lord's wish always
comes first with Foo.
《ヨウロウ : 理由はわからんが
なぜか素直になる》
I don't know why,
but she calmly obeys whenever
his name is mentioned.
フウ！ また！
どこへ行く！
Foo! Not again!
Where are you going?!
中央塔に決まってるっす！
To the central tower, where else?!
(ヨウロウ/ケゴン)なら逆！
あららっ。
– You're going the wrong way!
《カンクロウ : 砂の目ならば
身の危険はないが➡
With the Sand Eye,
there's no danger to him physically.
我愛羅の考えが
変わっていない以上…》
But as long as Gaara
doesn't change his mind…
《テマリ : 気を抜くわけには
いかないな》
We can't let down our guard.
我愛羅 飯にしないか？
Gaara…
Shall we break for dinner?
ああ 時間も時間だしな。
I agree. It's getting late.
(我愛羅)いや 今はいい。
(カンクロウ)そうか。
No, I'm okay right now.
All right.
(テマリ)フラれたな。
(カンクロウ)だな。
He snubbed us.
Sure did.
んっ！
(マツリ)どこへ向かってるの？
(ミコシ)ああ 中央塔に行く。
Where are we headed?!
We're heading to the central tower.
(マツリ)待って！
まだ巻物 揃ってない！
Wait, we don't have two scrolls!
(ミコシ)頭を使うんだ
俺たちには地の利がある。
Use your head!
The earth here is to our advantage!
(ユカタ)私たちが持ってるの
地の巻物じゃなくて➡
Actually, we don't have
the "Earth" scroll,
just the "Heaven" one.
天のほうだけど？
そういう意味じゃない！
That's not what I meant.
(ミコシ)天と地の書の巻物を
手に入れた者は➡
Any team with both "Heaven" and
"Earth" scrolls will be targeted.
他の班から狙われる。 だから➡
So they'll head straight
一目散に中央塔に向かうはずだ。
for the central tower
as quickly as possible.
ところが その周囲には➡
But, traps are laid throughout
the surrounding area.
さまざまなトラップが
仕掛けられている。
Except this eastern route.
この東のルートを除いてはな。
(マツリ)東のルートは何もないの？
The eastern route is clear?
(ユカタ)そしたら みんな東のルートを
使うんじゃない？
Then everyone will
be using that route!
ところが ここには
自然の隠れ流砂があるんだ。
Except…this place has naturally
occurring hidden quicksand pits.
(ミコシ)そこに落ちて
抜け出せなくなった連中から➡
Once you fall in, you can't get out.
So we'll get there first, wait patiently,
and then steal a scroll.
巻物を奪うって寸法さ。
いい案だろ。
How's that plan?
さすが！
でも ちょっと気が引けるね。
You're so smart.
It sounds a bit cowardly though.
(ミコシ)二次試験 合格がかかってる。
Do you want to pass
the Second Exam or not?
きれいごとは
言ってられないだろ。
Don't be a hypocrite.
(マツリ)そうね やりましょう！
You're right. Let's do it.
((フギ : ほう お前がホウイチか
So you're Houichi.
まだ若いように見えるが。
You look quite young.
(ホウイチ)はい
確かに若くございます。
Yes, I am young.
しかし 幼き日より➡
But I've studied
the Priest Bunpuku's power
分福様の流れをくむ
法力を学びました。
to mold currents since I was a child.
(フギ)ほう 分福…。
Bunpuku, you say?
(ホウイチ)はい。
Yes.
我愛羅様は 風影になった今でも➡
Gaara has become the Kazekage,
里にとって危険な存在だ。
but he still poses
a threat to this village.
それが あるかぎり➡
As long as he remains,
恐怖による支配という
構図が変わることはない。
measures are necessary
to control this fear.
こたびの中忍試験は一尾➡
The Chunin Exams present
the ideal opportunity
守鶴を抜く またとない機会。
to extract Shukaku the One Tail.
もっとも それは➡
Ultimately, this means
that he must die.
あのお方の死をも
意味することだがな。
(はい))
Yes.
《フギ : まずは 風影を自由にして➡
First, we must make sure
the Kazekage is alone,
塔から おびき出すとするか。
and lure him to the tower.
遠距離感知を妨げていた結界を➡
I'll now release the barrier
今 解き放つ。
that obstructed long-range
sensory perception.
魔の砂漠と呼ばれるのは➡
This place is called Demon Desert
because it's difficult to survive
一度 巻き込まれたら最後➡
its massive sandstorms
once you get stuck in one.
生き延びるのは難しい
大砂嵐のせい。
それゆえ 砂の探査班は➡
That's why
the Sand Investigative Unit
常に遠距離感知を張り➡
uses long-range sensory perception
and stays on guard.
警戒している》
(ネジ)うっ なに!?
What?!
(リー)何ですか あれは!?
What is that?
Hey, this is bad!
(テンテン)ちょっと これ
やばいんじゃない？
《フギ : しかし 遠距離感知が
機能していなかったら➡
However, if long-range sensory
perception wasn't functioning,
what would happen?
どうなるか？》
《フギ : 今頃 本部は大騒ぎだろう》
By now, chaos must be
breaking out at headquarters…
大規模な砂嵐が
突如 発生しました！
A massive sandstorm is forming!
なんで今まで
見つけられなかった？
Why wasn't it
detected until now?!
それが 何の異常も
なかったのです。
I didn't sense anything unusual!
ええ こっちにも全然。
He's right. I didn't detect
anything either.
何者かが遠距離感知に
干渉したのでは？
Could someone be interfering
with our long-range sensory...?
(カンクロウ)結界でも作って
感知を邪魔してたってのか。
Like blocking your perception
with a barrier?!
誰が 何の目的で？
Who would do this, and why?
そんなことよりも➡
More important, we have to come up
with safety measures
受験者への対策が先だ。
for the exam participants first!
受験者は サバイバルするのも➡
Isn't survival part of this exam?
試験のうちじゃねえのか？
This sandstorm is way too big!
この砂嵐 でかすぎだよ。
There will be hell to pay
if they all die.
全員が死んじまったら
困るだろうが。
チェッ 世話が焼けるやつらだ。
Damn it!
What a hopeless bunch.
二次試験を 一時中断。
The Second Exam will
be postponed temporarily…
受験者たちを シェルターに誘導する。
and we'll lead all
the exam participants into shelters.
そこの２人 風影様を頼む。
I leave the Kazekage to you two,
because it seems like he's going
to take matters into his own hands...
あいつ 自分で救出に行く
って言いそうじゃん？
絶対に表に出さないように。
Make sure he does not
set foot outside.
(２人)ハッ！
– Yes sir!
(テマリ)準備は いいか？
(みんな)ハッ！
Are you ready?
– Yes, ma'am!
(カンクロウ)一班 二班 三班は俺と。
Teams One to Three,
come with me.
(テマリ)残りの班は 私とともに。
The rest, with me!
続け！
Let's go!
これほど大規模な砂嵐を➡
I can't believe we didn't detect
a sandstorm of this magnitude.
感知できずにいたとは。
いったい 誰が
邪魔をしていたんだ？
Who could have interfered?
何も起きなければ いいんだが。
I just hope
nothing bad happens…
ああ。
そうだな。
Yeah. I agree.
くっ… 何よ これ!?
What is this—?!
砂嵐です。
うっ。
It is a sandstorm!
I know that!
そんなこと知ってるわよ！
ゴホッ ゴホッ。
これが 魔の砂漠の大砂嵐か。
So this what a giant sandstorm
of the Demon Desert is like.
思った以上に規模がでかい。
It's way bigger than I imagined.
このままでは まずいな。
We can't stay here, that's for sure.
ヌヌヌ…。
こいつはひでえな。
This is bad…
だから とっとと中央塔に
向かってりゃよかったんだよ！
That's why I insisted on
going straight to the central tower!
(フウ)危な！
Watch out!
ん？ どうしたの？
イテテ…。
What's wrong?
何でもない…。
Uh, nothing.
砂嵐か。
これでますます地の利が。
A sandstorm huh…?
This gives us
the home-court advantage.
っていうレベルじゃないでしょ！
I really wouldn't say that now...
こいつはひどいな。
This is bad.
ここまで巨大な嵐は久しぶりだ。
We haven't seen a storm
this massive in quite a while.
Yeah, I hope the exam participants
are all right.
ああ。 受験者は大丈夫だろうか。
そうだな。 あっ 風影様は？
Yeah...
Hey, where is Lord Kazekage?
大丈夫だ。
おとなしくしておられる。
He's fine. He's staying put.
よかった。
ああ。
That's good.
Yeah…
(テンテン)うわぁ！
一寸先も見えない…。
I can't even see an inch
in front of me!
(リー)なんのこれしき！
中央塔まであとわずか。
It's just a little sand!
The central tower is
right up ahead.
根性で乗り切りましょう！
Let's overcome this
with gutsiness!
白眼！
Byakugan!
根性で乗り切れるような
規模じゃない。
This is going to take a lot more
than gutsiness to overcome...
この近くで 砂嵐を
やり過ごせる場所を探そう。
Let's look for a spot nearby
to wait out the storm.
目が 目が開けられない。
I can't open my eyes!
うっ… 砂が刺さる。
The sand stings!
グハッ… 息ができない。 ゴホッ ゴホッ。
I-I can't breathe…
グッ… ダメだ。
I can't…hang on…
Use this.
これを使え。 防砂マントだ。
It's a sand mask!
The Second Exam is
temporarily postponed!
(カンクロウ)二次試験は一時中断だ。
お前らをシェルターに誘導する。
We'll take you to the shelter.
こんな砂嵐なんかに
負けんじゃねえ！
Don't give in to
a sandstorm like this!
(テマリ)カマイタチ！
Wind Scythe!
さあ 今のうちに進め。
All right, now's your chance
to move forward!
Come on, hurry!
さっさと急げ！
大丈夫なの？ リー。
Are you okay, Lee?!
これだけ激しい砂嵐だと➡
My Hidden Leaf cloak isn't much help
against a sandstorm this bad.
木ノ葉のマントくらいじゃ
どうにもなりませんね。
(ネジ)よし ならば…。
All right, then…
八卦掌回天！
Eight Trigrams Palm, Rotation!
テンテン！ 今だ！
Now, Tenten!
任せといて。
Leave it to me!
I think I have something that
will help us block the sandstorm!
砂嵐を防ぐんなら
あれが使えそう！
ENDURANCE
Let's go inside and
sit out this storm.
さあ この中に入って
砂嵐をやり過ごすのよ！
(リー)はい！
(ネジ)よし。
– Okay!
– Yes!
(リー)よくこんなものを
用意していましたね。
I'm amazed you had
something like this handy.
まあ こういうことでもないと
私の出番ないからね。
Situations like these are
the only times I'm useful.
なるほど。
さすがだ。
I see!
As expected.
(テンテン)どっちか否定しなさいよ！
At least one of you refute me!
あっ…。
(ユカタ)もうダメ 歩けない…。
I can't walk any further…
頑張れ！ もう少しで中央塔だ！
Hang in there!
We're almost at the central tower!
Are you sure about that?
ほんとに間違いないの？
さっきから 全然 到着しないけど。
You've been saying that,
but we haven't reached it yet…
間違いない！ うわぁ！
I'm sure!
(２人)あっ！
見ろ！
Look! The hidden quicksand!
隠れ流砂だ！
間違いなかったぞ！ うわぁ！
See, I was right!
(マツリ)そんなこと
言ってる場合じゃないでしょ！
This is not time to be saying that!
うっ うっ… うわぁ～！
ミコシ！
ああ！
Mikoshi!
しっかり！
ミコシを引っ張り上げるわよ！
Hang on!
We're going to pull
Mikoshi out of there.
うん！
うぅ～ん！
Okay!
(マツリ/ユカタ)うぅ～ん！
流される！ うっ…。
I-I'm sinking!
(２人)うぅ～ん！
(マツリ/ユカタ)うっ うぅ～！
(ホウイチ)そろそろか。
Pretty soon now…
ぐっ… うぅ…。
はっ… うっ…。
(２人)うぅ～ん！
もう少し！
Almost there!
(マツリ)さぁ つかまって！
Now! Grab my hand!
ああっ！
(３人)うわぁ！
(ケゴン)ペッ ペッ… たまんねぇ…。
I can't stand this!
We'd better make it to
the central tower fast
(ヨウロウ)早いとこ
中央塔に逃げないと➡
遭難してしまうぞ。
or we'll be swallowed up.
(マツリたち)うわぁ！
((シブキ : うっ…。
シブキ！
Shibuki!
(シブキ)大丈夫。 俺が必ず守るから。
It's okay!
I will always protect you.
Why?
どうして…。
ん？
どうして守ってくれたっす？
Why did you protect me?
お前が大切だからに
決まってるだろ。
Because you're precious to me.
Why else?
だから お前も大切な人を守れ。
That's why you have to protect
those who are dear to you too.
人と人が つながれば
この世に争いなどなくなる。
If people bond with each other,
there wouldn't be wars in this world.
(まずは
100人の友を作ることだ))
So first, make a hundred friends.
What is it, Foo?
どうした？ フウ。
中央塔は あっちだぞ。
The central tower is that way!
おい 聞いてるのか？ うっ！
Hey, are you listening?
(ケゴン)シブキ様が！
(ヨウロウ)シブキ様のために！
Lord Shibuki will—!
For Lord Shibuki's sake—!
シブキも これから
あっしのすることを➡
I'm sure Shibuki will be pleased
with what I'm going to do now!
きっと喜んでくれるっす！
(２人)ああ…。
(３人)うっ うぅ…。
ああ… うぅ…。
ハッ！
よし！ おとなしくしてるっす！
All right! Stay still!
それ！
この…。
Come on!
ん？
砂隠れの里 風影 我愛羅だ。
滝隠れのフウっす。
I am Gaara, the Kazekage of
the Village Hidden in the Sand.
I'm Foo from
the Hidden Waterfall Village.
なぜ助けた？
お前も中忍試験の受験者だろう。
Why did you save them?
You're taking the Chunin Exams too,
aren't you?
ああ… 里長のシブキが
教えてくれたっす。
Oh... Our village chief, Shibuki,
taught me.
((シブキ…。
多くの人は お前のことを➡
Shibuki?
Many people might
misunderstand you.
誤解しているかもしれない。
しかし お前は
自分の周りの人々を➡
But you must hold
the people around you dear…
大切に思い 大切な人のために
尽くせばいい。
And do your best
for these people.
そうすれば きっと…。
100人の友が できるっすね！
If you do, then someday…
I'll have a hundred friends, right?
(え？ あ… ああ))
Y-Yes…
きっと いつか100人の友が
できるって教えてくれたっす！
He taught me that one day
I'm sure to have 100 friends.
そうか それでか。
え？
I see, that's why…
お前を見ていて
ある男を思い出していたが➡
As I watched you,
I remembered a certain man…
その理由がわかった。
And now, I know why.
誰なんすか？ その男って。
Who is this man?
お前に よく似た男だ。
俺はそいつと戦い➡
He's a lot like you.
I faced him in battle…
触れ合うことで
他者と 苦しみや悲しみ➡
And he taught me
that we can learn
to understand the pain and sorrow,
and the joy of others.
喜びも分かち合うことが
できるんだと教えられた。
へえ～ そんな男がいるんなら➡
Wow… I'd like to meet someone
like that and become his friend.
あっしも会って
友達になりたいっす！
う… うぅ…。
お前たち 何の巻物持ってるっす？
Hey, what scroll do you guys have?
天の巻物を…。
The "Heaven" scroll…
(３人)あ…。
持っていくっす。
Take it!
ほ… ほんとですか？
助かっちゃった。
Really?!
You're a lifesaver!
ダメよ。 それは いただけません。
We can't.
We can't accept it.
どうしてっす？ あっしは➡
Why not?
I have a new goal,
so I don't need it!
新しい目的ができたから
いらないし…。
私たちは 我愛羅様に
教えていただきました。
We were taught by Lord Gaara…
(マツリ)自分の力で
自分が作った壁を➡
To break down the barriers
that we create,
打ち破り 勝つ方法を…。
to overcome and win,
and grasp the results that we desire.
どうやれば 結果をつかむことが
できるのかを。
その巻物は のどから
手が出るほど欲しいけど➡
We want that scroll
more than anything,
あなたから貰っては
二次試験の条件を➡
but if we allow you
to give it to us…
we can't claim that we fulfilled
the conditions of the Second Exam.
クリアしたとは言えません。
私たちは 私たちの力で➡
We will obtain it through
our own power.
手に入れてみせます。
わかったっす。
I understand!
(ケゴン/ヨウロウ)フウ!!
– Foo!
捕まると面倒だから
んじゃ これで失礼するっす！
It'll be a pain if they catch me…
So, I'll be going now!
さよなら。
Good bye!
(３人)ありがとう！
– Thank you!
She's interesting…
《おもしろいやつ。 いずれ また➡
I'm sure we'll meet again somewhere.
どこかで会うこともあるだろう》
(ホウイチ)我愛羅様 お覚悟ください。
Lord Gaara…
Prepare to die.